Hirut Assefa Gebrekidan



Hirutassefa04@yahoo.com

in/hirutassefa/

https://github.com/ HirutAssefa

+420 601 333 416

Skills

- Manual testing
- API Testing (Postman)
- JIRA, Zepher, Trello
- MySQL
- HTML5, CSS/SASS/Bootstrap
- JAVASCRIPT/Typescript
- Basic JAVA & C#
- Git/Github
- Visual Basic

Education

2020-2021

 Object Oriented Programming (OOP) and Visual Basic, VŠB-TU Ostrava (in Czech)

2016-2020

 Master's degree in development studies, Charles University, Prague (in Czech)

2002-2006

 Bachelor of Education, Bahir Dar University, Ethiopia (in English)

Languages

- English: Advanced
- Czech: Intermediate

Certification

- ISTQB Certified Tester, Foundation Level
- Google Analytics for Beginners

Other

- Driving license, B1
- EU residence permit

About me

Hello, I'm Hirut Assefa, a software tester at uTest with proficiency in testing. I have experience in creating comprehensive test documentation, including test scenarios, test cases, requirement traceability matrices, and bug reports. Additionally, I am familiar with defect management tools, Agile methods, web technologies, version control (Git/GitHub), MySQL databases, and API testing.

click here to view my portfolio

Projects

Project 1: Testing the registration form (manual testing)

 In this project I show my skills in manual testing. I thoroughly tested the registration form, which I created using HTML, CSS and Bootstrap. This project demonstrates my ability to create test scenarios, design test cases, ensure they meet requirements, and report any issues I find <u>View source code</u>

Project 2: Website for a marketing agency

• Frontend: HTML for structure, css for style and javascript for interactivity <u>View source code</u> <u>view the web page</u>

Experiences

Software tester - uTest

02/2023 - present

- Good knowledge of manual testing
- Knowledge of Postman tools
- Knowledge of the principles of Agile development (SCRUM)
- Knowledge of JIRA, Zephyr and Trello
- Knowledge of programming languages (Javascript and Typescript)
- Knowledge of using version control systems such as Git/Github
- Knowledge of working with databases, especially MySQL
- Desire to learn new things, diligence, reliability and responsibility

Maternity leave and career transition into IT

2016-2023

2012-2013

 During maternity leave, I completed my master's degree, learned to program and created personal projects using html, css and javascript

Saleswoman and team leader - Towers Cafe, 2013-2016

Praguen teams in customer service, product knowledge

English teacher - Children's club, Beroun

preparation of interactive teaching materials

Assistant Officer and geography teacher (UNHCR 2011–2012 Project) - Jijiga, Ethiopia

• Providing administrative support and Teacher

Geography teacher, secondary school, Addis 2007–2011